The biggest problem in AI right now can
be described with a single word,
sycophancy. You've probably heard of
this before, but it means that AI models
tend to agree with us and reinforce our
opinions and their own way too much.
They have too much bias. And the problem
here is that sycophancy, it actually
seems to be getting worse as large
language models are getting more
powerful, not better. Now, when people
talk about sycophancy and AI, they're
usually referring to the more broader
sense of just any conversation with a
large language model. But honestly, this
hits the most with AI coding because the
worst thing you can do is have a coding
agent evaluate its own work. You know,
the conversation where you just injected
a ton of your opinions and there's a lot
of bias built up as the agent wrote the
code. It's going to give itself a gold
star every time because it's like a
student grading their own homework. They
might point out a couple of flaws to
make the review seem legit, but in the
end the bigger problems are stuffed
under the rug and they're going to cause
big problems when you're using your code
base for real. Okay, well, that kind of
sucks. So, cool. What's the solution
here? Well, if you haven't tried to
giving your coding agent a sparring
partner before, you're definitely going
to want to after watching this video.
I'm talking a totally separate coding
agent with its own context session where
its sole job is to rip apart to the main
agent's implementation. I call it
adversarial dev because you're creating
the second agent to be nitpicky, to play
devil's advocate and question even the
deeper decisions made in the code base.
And yes, going from a single agent to a
multi-agent setup has some overhead.
We'll talk about that as well, but man,
the results that we get from this speak
for themselves. So, if you are
wondering, yes, I'm going to get very
practical for you in this video showing
you exactly how to create this
adversarial dev architecture. We're
going to take a lot of inspiration from
Anthropic and so I'll cover this new
blog post from them. One unfortunate
thing about this though is they share a
lot of good stuff here, but they haven't
actually open-sourced anything like they
have in previous blog articles like this
one. And so, I've taken it upon myself
to create everything from the ground up.
I've created a Claude and Codex version
of these harnesses, and you could even
mix these to have Claude be the
implementer and Codex be the evaluator.
And so, I'll show you how I built this,
and then of course, I've got a diagram
here to explain everything. So, I'm
going to break it down nice and simple,
and really this is the future of AI
coding. Having separate coding agents
work together to accomplish larger tasks
more reliably. So, let's get into this.
So, if you've been following Anthropic's
research, you know that they've been
working pretty hard on making Claude
better at building front-ends and
improving their long-running coding
agent harness, answering the question,
"How far can we push the limits for
coding agents?" And so, they've been
building a lot on top of the harness
that they covered in this blog post. I
actually cover this in a video that I'll
link to right here, but with their
evolution now, they've been taking a lot
of inspiration from generative
adversarial networks. And this is where
it gets really interesting. If you're
not familiar with GANs, it's a machine
learning approach where we have one
model generate images, and then another
model is the discriminator. The
discriminator's sole job is to figure
out what images are real from some kind
of real data set we feed in versus which
ones were generated by the other model.
And so, the sole job of the generator is
to trick the discriminator. And in
getting better and better at tricking
the discriminator, it actually makes
more and more realistic images over
time. So, it's a very interesting
approach to train it to make accurate
images. And so, we're taking inspiration
from that, now applying it to large
language models and coding agent
harnesses. And so, we're extrapolating
that idea into having the generator and
evaluator agent, just like I was saying
earlier.
And so, this article is a very
interesting read. I'll link to this in
the description, of course. They talk
about why naive implementations fall
short, as in just having a single coding
agent session, and then they get into
their approach. They actually have three
agents here. So, they have the planner
to help create the initial spec, and
then we go through the loop of the
generator and the evaluator. And I could
just read through this entire article,
but I wanted to make it really easy for
you to grasp everything here. So, I've
created a diagram to explain it all. So,
we'll get to that in just a sec, but one
more thing I want to show you here is
the kinds of things that we can build
with this harness. I'll show you both
Anthropic and myself. So, for their
testing, they tried using both the
single agent and this harness to build a
retro game maker. So, you can define
your own sprites and even play the game
after. And so, what we're looking at
here is what the single agent made. It
looks pretty cool overall, but when they
got to the actual gameplay, nothing was
working. So, as far as the first pass,
you know, the first iteration went, it
was pretty underwhelming. And so, of
course, you can iterate, but the point
of a harness is you don't have to. You
can just send off a task and it'll go
through the process of iterating itself.
And so, that's exactly what they did.
This is the second version built with
the harness, where we had the evaluator
being very nitpicky, basically fighting
with the implementer. And so, we have
our opening screen, the sprite editor,
that looks even a lot more elaborate,
the game design, so building your
different levels, and then the gameplay,
this time it actually worked. And so,
this isn't like a video that we can
watch or anything, but they were able to
play the game. And pretty cool. I don't
want to just take the article at face
value though, and so with this whole
harness that I built for you, I also ran
it entirely to build a pretty elaborate
application. I created this app where it
ingests my YouTube content and has a
full rag pipeline working in the back
end, and then we have a front end here
where we can ask any questions that we
want. So, I can send this in. This
actually works with a large language
model under the hood. It has a very,
very polished UI. Like, I'm super
impressed overall. We got token
streaming and everything. Like, really,
really cool. So, this is the kind of
thing even like shows the sources at the
bottom here. Like, I know that a single
coding agent session would not have been
able to create something this elaborate.
But, I did one shot it, right? Like, of
course, there's a lot more agents doing
work under the hood, but the point is
for me, I just sent in a single request
for this application and I had it rip
through it over the course of about 4
hours, actually, iterating on this. And,
man, it's super impressive. Like, these
are the kinds of things we can do when
we let agents work together and just go
ham. And, yeah, 4 hours does mean a lot
of tokens, but the thing is these
harnesses, they enable us to start using
faster and cheaper models and still get
really good results. Plus, the
reliability is just really worth
overhead for me. So, we'll talk about
that more at the end of the video. But,
right now, I want to get into the
harness diagram here and show you
exactly how this works, how you can run
my example for yourself, as well. The
sponsor of today's video is Scrimba.
I've covered their full stack developer
course before, but not their AI
engineering path. And, it is very
value-packed. It covers building AI
agents, rag, model context protocol,
prompt engineering, everything you need.
And, they built it in partnership with
Hugging Face and LangChain. And, you get
to build things the entire time you're
going through the course. So, this is
not just your average data science or
machine learning course. It's made for
web developers who want to build a
gentic applications. And, what makes
Scrimba stand out over all other code
learning platforms is that any point we
can pause the lesson, like right here,
and then we can edit the instructor's
code. So, it's super easy to learn by
doing. So, for example, I can change the
GPT model here. And, then I can also
change the system prompt for the agent
in this example. And, then I can run the
application and I can test things live.
Take a look at this. I'll go ahead and
say hi. And now we'll get a response in
pirate talk. Very cool. There are also
challenges built throughout the lessons
with AI for instant feedback, so you're
never just passively watching. You're
always building. Scrimba also has some
free courses for you to try things out,
but I would highly recommend trying the
AI engineer path. I'll have a link in
the description to save 20% on the pro
plan, which unlocks everything in
Scrimba. So, the entire system starts
off with your user prompt. Very simply,
you just have to specify what you want
to build. And the beauty of this is the
planner is going to expand your prompt
into a full spec that's optimized for
the harness, so you don't have to worry
about being overly specific. And so,
within the repository that I'll link to
in the description, where I have both
the Claude and Codex harnesses, I also
have the example prompt. This is exactly
what I sent in to both harnesses to
build versions of the Rag application
that I shared earlier. And so, yeah,
build a full-stack Rag app that looks
and feels like a premium AI chat
platform like ChatGPT or Claude.ai, blah
blah blah. I describe my tech stack,
basically injecting all of the opinions
I want to, but you can be as specific or
unspecific as you would like. So, you
take this as your initial prompt, and
then you send that into the planner. And
the planner's sole job, I'll actually
show you what it looks like here. In
both the Claude and Codex harnesses, we
have the planner here. It's sole job is
to take in the user prompt, and then
produce the spec. And that is going to
guide the rest of our harness. And so,
you can see with both the Claude and
Codex versions, we have the evaluator,
right? We got the generator, we have the
harness that ties it all together, the
planner. All of these I've set up very
purposely in the exact same way to show
you that we don't have to stick to
Anthropic just because we're taking
inspiration from an Anthropic article.
And then within the uh shared folder
here, I have all the prompts for the
different stages. So, like this is our
planner here. You are a product
architect. Your job is to take a brief
user description. That's our prompt
markdown. And then produce a
comprehensive product specification. And
then everything else in the prompt here
is just describing the structure that we
want for our specs so we can make it
reliable and repeatable between all of
our different harness executions. Very,
very neat. And then once we have our
spec, this is where we go into our
sprint cycle. And this is the most
fascinating part of the entire system.
Because before we go into writing a
single line of code, we're actually
going to have the generator and
evaluator negotiate a contract. So
they're going to decide up front here
are the different phases that we're
going to go through to break up the
spec. And here's how we're going to
evaluate each phase. So yes, it is
adversarial, right? Like the evaluator
is going to rip apart the generator's
implementation, but they're agreeing on
what that battle looks like up front. So
it's very ethical. They have some
etiquette establishing here going into
what this build is going to look like.
So let me go back to the code base and
show you my example of this. So what
you're looking at right here is the
final spec that the planner agent
produced when it was building my rag
YouTube chat application. And so you can
look at the harness.ts if you want to
like see the full workflow, how this is
coded. But once we have the spec from
the planner, then again, we send that
into negotiation. Both the implementator
and evaluator agents are going to agree
on how they're going to split the larger
spec into manageable chunks through
these different sprints. We definitely
don't want to send this entire thing
into the agent to knock out at once. And
so we're splitting up the work. So
here's our first sprint. Here are the
different features that we need our
implementator to build. And then here's
the criteria that our evaluator agent is
going to judge against. And you can see
that we have a description of like
here's what the evaluator's going to
judge. And then we have the threshold.
It's going to give a score of 1 to 10
for each one of these criteria. And so
as long as it meets the threshold or
exceeds, then the implementer did a good
job, right? Like we can move on from
that single criteria. If everything
passes here, then we can move on to the
next sprint. And so going back to the
idea of GANs, right? Cuz this is a
GAN-inspired harness. Essentially, the
generator is trying to, you could say,
trick the evaluator into thinking that
the application is working. And if the
evaluator is judging correctly, then
it's not really being tricked. It's like
the application is actually good. But
you you get the idea there how we're
relating it back to having these
adversarial agents that are battling it
out just like with the old machine
learning approach. Because basically,
the generator, once it gets feedback
from the evaluator and it retries a
maximum of three times, its sole job is
just to appease the evaluator. So, we
rely on the criteria of actually
pointing towards the application working
correctly. But as long as that's the
case, then if it's doing everything in
its power to appease or trick the
evaluator, then the application is
working. We go through iterating on all
the sprints, and then we end up with a
working application. And so yeah, this
is not going to be perfect. Coding
agents are never going to be perfect.
But the idea here is that instead of us
having to guide these different sprints
and us having to work through all the AI
slop and provide all the feedback
ourself, we're setting up a system where
a lot of that is taken care of for us.
And that is a beautiful thing. So, I
would encourage you to just download
this repository and try out either the
Claude or Codex harness. It's going to
take you 5 minutes to get up and
running, and you can build incredible
things very quickly. Not that you would
use this harness to create something
that's immediately production-ready, but
helping you create proofs of concepts
very quickly, getting started on your
next project. That's what I use these
kinds of harnesses for all of the time.
And then, yeah, at some point, this is
going to be the way to build anything
with AI coding assistance. And so, this
is worth getting in on right now. And
so, within the readme, I have a quick
start here. Super easy. We can use
either Claude code or Codex. And to my
knowledge, you are allowed to use your
Anthropic or Codex subscription with the
harness. So, you don't have to pay for
API credits. I know there's been a lot
of controversy recently around if we can
use our subscription with the Agent SDK.
Even some things in the Anthropic docs
that said that you couldn't. But, uh
Threek, he's one of the members of the
Anthropic team, he clarified that we are
allowed to use our subscription with the
Agent SDK or headless Claude mode as
long as it is for local development and
experimentation. So, if you're building
a business on top of the Agent SDK, as
in other people would be using your
script subscription, then it's against
the terms of service and you should use
your API key. So, for what we're doing
here, when you run the harness locally,
you can use your subscription for
either. So, you don't have to pay for
API credits. That would be obviously
quite expensive with a long-running
harness. And so, you just have to have
your authentication set up with either
one of these, whatever one you want to
run. And then, you clone the repository,
install the dependencies, and then it's
just a single command to kick off either
of the harnesses. And the best part is
you can use your coding agent to help
with this as well. So, you can say, you
know, I want to build XYZ. This is where
you can describe your application, your
tech stack, and things like that. And
then, it can help you create the
prompt.md that we have as our starting
point. And you can even have it read the
one that I have checked into the repo
here if you just want a starting point,
right? Like the general structure that I
used for my prompt.
And then, your coding agent can read the
readme so it knows how to kick off the
harness for you. I've never actually run
this command myself. As I was prepping
this video and building this and doing
all my testing, I would always just have
my Claude Coder Codex run this bun
command to kick off the whole process.
And so, very easy to get up and running
and doing this yourself. All you have to
work on is creating this initial prompt,
but then all the other prompts for the
planner, and we have the generator
system prompt for the software engineer,
and the evaluator, you're a skeptical QA
engineer, like all the other prompts are
already built into the system here, so
you just get to let it go. And it'll
create this back and then create the
sprints and work through them
automatically and then report back to
you when you have the final application.
It's so fun to just watch it go and then
come back to this beautifully working
application. So, the last thing that I
want to hit on really quickly here is
the downside of these harnesses.
Obviously, it's going to be a token
cost, right? When you have this full
specking process with the loop of
implementation and evaluation and
iteration, it's going to go on for a
long time. I mean, that's why these are
called harnesses for long-running
agents. But, the thing is, this is so
worth it to me. I mean, look at what I
was able to build here in just a single
shot. I mean, yes, there's a lot of
tokens that we spent here, but it would
take a while to get to this point if I
was working with a single agent myself.
And the kicker here is I use Claude
Sonnet 4.6 to build the entire thing.
You can see in the configuration I have
for the model I use for both Claude and
Codex. And let me tell you, Opus 4.6 is
way better than Sonnet 4.6. I have used
both extensively, and Opus 4.6 would not
have been able to one-shot this without
the harness, and Claude Sonnet did with
the harness. And so, you can try this
out yourself and and try smaller models,
and you'll see that like we could
actually save tokens with these
harnesses because now we're leaning more
into the system we build for AI coding
versus always relying on the most
reasoning power possible with these
bigger large language models. So, it's
definitely worth a a
And so, that's everything that I have
for you on this harness here. And I will
say, I'm going to be doing a lot more
content soon on these harnesses and just
showing you how far you can take them.
And so, if you appreciated this video
and you're looking forward to more
things on AI coding and these harnesses,
I would really appreciate a like and a
subscribe. And with that, I will see you
in the next video.